Guide to the John Singleton Papers, 1964-1981 UA.90.F67
ULS Archives & Special Collections
John Singleton Papers
1964-1981
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Singleton, John Calhoun
UA.90.F67
10.63 Linear Feet (9 boxes)
This collection consists of the papers, correspondence, and research of Dr. John Singleton. Singleton was a professor in the School of Education at the University of Pittsburgh, specializing in Anthropology and International Development Education. His primary areas of research were applied anthropology and developmental education, with a focus on Japan and the U.S. Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands.
Biography
Dr. John Singleton was born in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania on August 7, 1930. He earned an A.B. from Oberlin College in Mathematics and Education in 1952 and an A.M. from Haverford College in their Social and Technical Assistance Program. In 1953, Singleton also earned his first grade professional certificate for secondary teaching in North Dakota. Singleton earned his Ph.D. in International Development Education from Stanford University in 1965. Among Singleton's early positions were teaching mathematics and science at the Fort Totten Indian Reservation in North Dakota and working as an Education and Training Specialist in the Truk District of the U.S. Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands. Prior to coming to the University of Pittsburgh, Singleton spent three years at the University of Hawaii as Associate Director of the International Development Fellowships and Seminars
Scope and Content Notes
The collection consists primarily of Singleton's correspondence, which covers the course of his tenure at the University of Pittsburgh. This includes both incoming and outgoing correspondence. Also included is information on the International and Developmental Education Program (IDEP) and the Comparative and International Education Society (CIES).
The first part of the collection (boxes 1-7) contains folders of correspondence, conference and committee materials, and information files in alphabetical order. The second part of the collection (boxes 8-9) includes Singleton's correspondence files.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
A gift of John Singleton, 2003.
Previous Citation
John Singleton Papers, 1964-1981, UA.90.F67, University Archives, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
John Singleton Collection. RG 90/F-67, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh.
Comparative education; International education; University of Pittsburgh; University of Pittsburgh. International and Development Education Program; University of Pittsburgh -- Faculty -- Correspondence; Comparative and International Education Society; Singleton, John Calhoun -- Correspondence
- A, I.
  - General Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Adams, John (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Agriculture Development Council (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Ala'ilima, Fay (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - American Anthropological Association (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - American Anthropological Association- Symposium, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - American Anthropological Association- Proposal - Mexico City, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - American Anthropological Association- Meetings, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - AERO Meetings, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - American Association for Advancement of Science (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - American Association for Advancement of Science Symposium - Places, Workers, and People, February 12-17, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - American Educational Research Association (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - American Friends Research Association (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - American Friends Research Association- Philadelphia Office (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Anderson, Arnold (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Anthropology Cirriculum Project (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Anthropology Department (Correspondence) (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Anthropology of Education Course Proposal (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Aoyama, Sachiyo (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Aries Corporation (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Arvizu, Steven (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Asia Foundation (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Asian Studies Program Advisory Committee (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Asian Studies Committee (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Asian Studies Committee, Japan and China Groups (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Asian Studies Committee, Bibliography, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Association for Anthropology in Micronesia (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Association for Social Anthropolgy in Oceania (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Atsumi, Reiko (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Ayambe, Tsuneo (Box 1, Folder 30)
- B, II.
  - General Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Ballendorf, Dirk A. (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Barnett, Milton (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Barnhardt, Ray (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Baty, Harvey (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Baty, Roger (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Beck, Carl (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Befu, Harumi (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Bereday, George Z. F. (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Bixby, Paul (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Bloomsburg State College (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Boulding, Kenneth (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Brameld, Theodore (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Brembeck, Cole (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Brown, Keith (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Burger, Henry G. (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Butts, R. Freeman (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Brown, Keith -- Proposal (Box 1, Folder 48)
- C, III.
  - General Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Capan, David (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Carlson, Paul (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Cassell, Joan (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Center for Asian Studies Meeting (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Chance, Norman (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Chantavanich, Supang (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Chapman, Nancy (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Chapman, Murry (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Chilcott, John -- Editor, CAE Newsletter (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Chinese University of Hong Kong Proposal (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Chung, Bom Mo (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - CIES Nominating Committee (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - CISS Seminar (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Clairton Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Cleary, Edward (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Cohen, Rosalie (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Comparative and Int. Education Conference (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Comparative Education -- Conference, October 17, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Comparative Education -- Conference Meeting, February 25, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Comparative Education -- Review (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Committee of Concerned Asian Scholars (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Committee on International Exchange of Persons (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Condon, Rick (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Conference on Traditional Korean Society and Culture, June 6-12, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Coombs, Philip (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Cormack, Margaret (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Corraoles, Zulema (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Correa, Hector (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Council on Anthropology and Education -- Finances (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Council on Anthropology and Education (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Joan Robers Papers (requests) (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Cowley, W.H. (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Coy, Michael (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Cummings, Richard (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Cummings, William (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Curle, Adamn (Box 2, Folder 37)
- D, IV.
  - General Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Department of State (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Deustcher, Irwin (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - DeVos, George (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - DeVries, Egbert (GSPIA) (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - DiBona, Joseph (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Dixon, Norman (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Dobbert, Marion (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Dulyachinda, S. (Box 2, Folder 46)
- E, V.
  - General Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - East-West Center (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - East-West Center, Internation Development Fellowships (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Ebuchi, Kazukimi (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Education and World Affairs (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Educational Anthropology (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Education and World Affairs (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - ERIC (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - ERIC, Proposals, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Erickson, Frederick (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Everhart, Robert B. (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - EWA Conference on Training and Educational Planning (Box 2, Folder 58)
- F, VI.
  - General Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Fahim, Hussein (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Fine, Judy (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Fischer, John L. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Fitzgerald, Thomas (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Flack, Michael (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Floyd, Vircher (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - FAFP -- Consultantship (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Foley, Douglas (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Ford Foundation (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Foreign Area Fellowship Program (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Friends Committee on Education and Research (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Friends of Micronesia (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Fuchs, Estelle (Box 3, Folder 15)
- G, VII.
  - General Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Gearing, Fred (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Gianotta, Frank (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Gibson, Greta (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Gibson, Rebert E. (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Gladwin, Thomas (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Goldschmidt, Walter (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Goetz, Judith Preissle (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Gondo, Yoshio (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Goodenough, Ward H. (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Goodman, Paul (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Greb, Edward (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Greene, Felix (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Griffin, Willis (Box 3, Folder 29)
- H, VIII.
  - General Corespondence (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Hackett, Peter (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Hall, William S. (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Han, Sang Bok (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Hansen, Judith (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Harvard Center for Studies and Educational Development (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Hawkins, James (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Hayward State College (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Heneveld, Ward (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Hezel, Francis X. (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Hetzel, Fredrick (University Press) (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Hezel, Francis (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Highlights (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Hill, Jacquetta (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Hill, Peter (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Hill, Robert (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Howard, F. Hjelm (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Hoffman, Harol (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Holt, Rhinehart, and Winston, Inc. (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Holznar, Burkhart (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Hoopes, David (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Hopkins, Frank Snowden (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Howard, Lawrence (GSPIA) (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Hughes, Dan (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Human Organization (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Hymes, Dell (Box 3, Folder 55)
- I, IX.
  - General Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - IDEP Faculty (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - IDEP Students (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - ILCORK (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - ILCORK Proposal (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Inagaki, Tadahiko (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Indian Rights Association (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Indigenous Anthropology (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Indonesia -- BP3K Project (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Institute for Local Self-reliance (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Institute for World Order, Inc. (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Institution Building in National Development (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - International and Development Education Program at University of Pittsburgh (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - International Dimensions Committee (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - International House of Japan (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - International Newsletter (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - International Review of Education (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Isidro, Antonio (Box 4, Folder 3)
- J, X.
  - General Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Jacobs, Sue-Ellen (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Japan Foundation, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Japan Foundation, Newsletter (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Japanese Studies (University of Pittsburgh) (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Johnson, Faye O. (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Johnson, Norman (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Johnson, William H.E. (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Journal of Asian and African Studies (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Journal of Asian History (Box 4, Folder 13)
- K, XI.
  - General Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Kaigo, Tokiomi (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Kaplan, Bernice A. (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Katz, Saul (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Kelly, Jim (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Kentucky, University of (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Kim, Kyung-Dong (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Kimball, Solon (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - King, A. Richard (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Konan University Exchange (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Kyushu University (Box 4, Folder 24)
- L, XII.
  - General Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Lancy, David (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Landy, David (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Laska, John A. (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Lauria, Jr., Anthony (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Lee, Hahn-Been (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Leestma, Robert (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Lehman, Edward (AAA) (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Lerich, Leo (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Lewis, Diane K. (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Linsley, Katherine S. (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Mc, XIII.
  - General Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - McCoy, Dean Richard (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - McCusker, Henry F. (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - McDermott, Ray (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - McGloin, Gale (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - McGough, James (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - McKnight, Robert K. (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - McPherron, Mrs. Stase (Box 4, Folder 43)
- M, XIV.
  - General Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Malcolm Martin Marcus Program (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Manalang, Priscila (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Mann, Horace / Paul Masoner Lecture Committee (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Mason, Leonard (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Masoner, Paul H. (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Mattox, Travis (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Maxwell, William (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Merritt, Carolyn (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Metzgar, Eric (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Mexico City Trip, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Micronesian Program (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Mindana State University (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Modiano, Nancy (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Montgomer, Edison (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Monumenta Nipponica (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Moos, Felix (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Morehouse, Ward (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Muller, Mary C. (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Multi-D Program, LRDC (Box 4, Folder 63)
- N, XV.
  - General Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Narrowe, Judith (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - National Academy of Education (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - National Committee on United States-China Relation, Inc. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - National Institute for Educational Research, (Tokyo, Japan) (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - National Science Foundation Grants (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Negro Community Organization Material (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Nelson, Hal (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - New Zealand Council for Educational Research (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Nominations for CAE Positions (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Noguchi, Paul (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Norbeck, Edward (Box 5, Folder 12)
- O, XVI.
  - General Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Obern, Gay (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - OECD (Paris) (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Officer, James E. (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Ogbu, John (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Okatsu, Morihiko (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Osteen, Arthur (Box 5, Folder 19)
- P, XVII.
  - General Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Pain, Hyun Ki (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Parker, Franklin (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Passow, A. Harry (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Paul, Glendora B. (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Paulston, Christina (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Paulston, Rolland G. (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Peake, Charles H. (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Pearsall, Marion (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Penn Circle Community H.H. (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Pergamon Press, Inc. (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Perrino, Ben (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Peterson, John H., Jr. (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Phi Chi Theta (T. Mattox) (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Pi Lambda Theta (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Pierce, Douglas (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Pittsburgh Board of Public Education (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Pittsburgh Peace Coalition (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Pletcher, Robert- (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Pletcher, Robert- Dissertation Proposal (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Plotnicov, Leonard (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Polk, Theodore (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Porter, Willis P. (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Posvar, Chancellor (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Precourt, Walter (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Preliminary Planning Proposal (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Proposal for the Preperation of World Culture Teachers at University of Pittsburgh (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Puey, Dr. (Thailand) (Box 5, Folder 47)
- Q, XVIII.
  - General Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Cuirolgico, Delfin (Box 5, Folder 49)
- R, XIX.
  - General Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Rawski, Evelyn (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Research Conference on Urban Sub-Cultural Differences, March 1969 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Roberts, Joan I. (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Rosh, Donna (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Ross, Emma Jean (Box 5, Folder 55)
- S, XX.
  - General (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - General Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - St. Lawrence, Theodora (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Sanders, Donald P. (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Sarason, Seymour B. (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - Sato, Izumi (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - Scanlon, David (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Scaglion, Richard/Nora (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - Schensul, Steve/Jay (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - School Resources Committee on Faculty Research Fund Guidelines (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Schoyer, Preston (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - Schramm, Wilbur (Box 5, Folder 67)
  - Schwartz, Douglas (Box 5, Folder 68)
  - Scott, Foresman Co. (Box 5, Folder 69)
  - Scott, Marvin B. (Box 5, Folder 70)
  - Scovel, Janene (Box 5, Folder 71)
  - Seoul National University (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Seoul/Pitt Proposal (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Serano, Rodolfo (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Sheon, Aaron (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Shibanuma, Susumu (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Shiloh, Ailon (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Shin, Se-Ho (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Shulman, Frank (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Shoben, Joseph (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Siffin, William J. (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Simon, Hans (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Simpson, R.F. (University of Hong Kong) (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Singleton, John- CV (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Singleton, John- Book Orders (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Singleton, John- Faculty Workload Documents (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Singleton, John- China, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Singleton, John- Japan, 1981-1982 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Singleton, John- Korea -- KAS, December, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Singleton, John- Miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Singleton, John- Personal (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Singleton, John- Papers (Box 6, Folder 21, 21a, 21b)
  - Singleton, John- Draft of a New Outline of Education (IDEP) (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Singleton, John- Anthropological Models of Community Development and Cultural Transmission... (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Singleton, John- Schools and Rural Development: An Anthropological Approach (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Singleton, John- Education as a Cultural Process (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Singleton, John- Education, Planning, and Political Developments in Micronesia, Revision, September 7, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Singleton, John- Multi-Culturalism in Social Context (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Singleton, John- SAA Meetings, Tucson, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Singleton, John- Collaborative Research on Political Change in Micronesia (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Singleton, John- Empty Folder (not included) (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Singleton, John- Educational Planning and Political Development in Micronesia, (AAA Meetings), November 18, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Singleton, John- Empty Folder (not included) (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Singleton, John- Education and Ethnicity CER, October 1977 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Singleton, John- Papers (requests for) (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Singleton, John- Tribal Anthropology in the Educational Preserve, February 1977 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Singleton, John- Trip to Korea and Japan (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Singer, Marshall (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Sisay, Delphine (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Skovira, Robert (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Social Science Research Council (Joint Committee on Japanese Studies) (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Empty Folder (not included) (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Spaulding, Seth (Box 6, Folder 42-43)
  - Staley, Eugene (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Stalker, John (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Stanford Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - SIDEC Materials (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - State University of New York at Albany, Conference, November 15-16, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - St. Lawrence, Theodora Proposal -- Ethnographic Study of a Multi-cultural Middle School of Education (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Story, Bascom H. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Straka, Mrs. Pauline (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Strauss, Levi (Box 7, Folder 3)
- T, XXI.
  - General (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Takeuchi, Satoru (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Talbert, Carol (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Tandler, Fredrika (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Textor, Robert (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Thomas, Lawrence (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Thirtha, N.V. (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Tickner, Michael (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Tilman, Betty (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Tita, William Tiga (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Troup, Alice (Box 7, Folder 14)
- U, XXII.
  - General (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Udom, Warotamasikkhadit (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Umakoshi, Toru (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Umapathy, K. Setty (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - UNESCO (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - University Center for International Studies (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - University of Calgary -- Summer Program on Development Committee (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - University of California, Santa Barbara (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - University of Guam (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - University of Hawaii (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - University of Houston (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - University of the Philippines (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - University of Colorado (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - University of South Florida (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - University of Virginia (Anthropology of Education) (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - U.S. Educational Commission in Korea (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - U.S. Office of Education (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Urban Education Committee (Box 7, Folder 32-32a)
  - U.S. Trust Territory Paper (Box 7, Folder 33)
- V, XXIII.
  - General (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Van Leer Foundation Proposal (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Venezuela Proposal (Hart, Paulston, and Watson) (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Vital Issues (Box 7, Folder 37)
- W, XXIV.
  - General (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Wagatsuma, Hiroshi (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Walker, Rob (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Warnapala, W.A. Wiswa (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Washington Contacts (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Watson, Paul (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Weidner, Edward (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Weiler, Hans (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Wenner-Gren Foundation (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - Western Illinois University (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - Western Pennsylvania Academic Council on Problem of War and Peace (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - Westinghouse Learning Corporation (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - Wigren, Harold (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - Williams, Dorothy (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - Woodley, Charlotte (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - World Year Book of Education (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - Wormsley, William (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - Wormsley, Diane -- Early Childhood Education: Educators vs. Anthropologists (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - Wright, Edward R., Jr. (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - World Bank (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - Wu, H.T. (Box 7, Folder 58)
- X-Y-Z, XXV.
  - General (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - Yano, Takashi (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - Yazaki, Takeo (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - Yee, Albert (Box 7, Folder 62)
  - Yoshida, Teigo (Kyushu University) (Box 7, Folder 63)
  - Zumwinkle, Robert (Box 7, Folder 64)
- Singleton Correspondence Files, XXVI.
  - September 1982 - April 1983 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - May 1981 - August 1981 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - January 1980 - April 1980 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - September 1979 - December 1979 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - December 1978 - September 1979 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - February 1978 - April 1978 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - October 1977 - January 1977 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - March 1977 - June 1977 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - November 1976 - February 1977 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - July 1976 - September 1976 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - March 1976 - June 1976 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - December 1975 - February 1976 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - September 1975 - November 1975 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - April 1975 - August 1975 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - January 1975 - March 1975 (Box 8, Folder 15)